<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Cases on Foldie Links</title>
    <link>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Use Cases on Foldie Links</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Band</title>
      <link>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/big-band/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/big-band/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You play the trumpet in the big band &amp;ldquo;The Reluctant Syncopators&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Your band has PDFs of the scores stored on an online folder.&#xA;Some PDFs contain all voices (Song.pdf), some are split up into the different voices (Song-trumpet-2.pdf).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-a-playlist-for-a-gig&#34;&gt;Preparing a playlist for a gig&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#preparing-a-playlist-for-a-gig&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You took over the moderation of the gig, so you do not have much time between the songs.&#xA;Therefore you prepare a &lt;a href=&#34;https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/features/notes/&#34;&gt;playlist note&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You create a new note for the gig and make it the current note.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For each song in the gig list:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You find the relevant PDF score file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You open it with the built-in PDF viewer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Within the score file you find the starting page of the notes for your voice (trumpet 2).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You create a link from the current page and add it to the current note.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the gig, you just tap the next link from the playlist note to get to the relevant page of the next song.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/collaboration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You work in a crative team in the company &amp;ldquo;The fruiters&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Part of your work is creating, talking about and modifying many design documents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You and your team agree on the following setup and workflow:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You all share a single iCloud project folder &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt; with subdirectories &lt;strong&gt;Common&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Tom&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Peter&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Anna&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Within the subdirectories, your team create reasonable project-specific subfolders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tom, Peter and Anna first create different documents in their named folders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then they discuss the documents in a Facetime call.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The team puts documents and resources that all agree upon into &lt;strong&gt;Common&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;Now the refinement begins:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tom and Anna each want to work on their own vision for document &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Therfore they copy &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; into their named directory.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then they discuss the documents in a Facetime call,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;and agree on Anna&amp;rsquo;s version with small modifications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anna takes some of Tom&amp;rsquo;s changes and copies the result back to the &lt;strong&gt;Common&lt;/strong&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-foldie-help&#34;&gt;How can Foldie help?&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#how-can-foldie-help&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To support this workflow, every team member sets up&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are a researcher and you have collected a pile of related papers in PDF format.&#xA;You enjoy Foldie a lot, because in your research documents you include &lt;a href=&#34;https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/glossary/foldie-link/&#34;&gt;Foldie links&lt;/a&gt; to the papers and easily open them from there.&#xA;Now you want to try the &lt;a href=&#34;https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/features/metadata/&#34;&gt;Metadata&lt;/a&gt; feature of Foldie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You think of good paper attributes, such as &lt;strong&gt;author&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;topic&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;publication-year&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;quality&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cited-paper&lt;/strong&gt;. You add properties to the links to the papers. You study the inter-linking of papers using the metadata browser and find that a lot of papers cite paper &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;. Being a good researcher, you really read that paper, think hard and you find a flaw. You write a paper about that and prove 20 other papers wrong. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutor</title>
      <link>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/tutor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://foldieapp.webli.de/en/docs/use-cases/tutor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are a private tutor and, because you are not enrolled in an official school, you and your pupils cannot use Apple&amp;rsquo;s Schoolwork app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You have prepared a folder &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; of resources and assignment documents (PDF, Pages), that your pupils should fill in.&#xA;You have also prepared folder &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt; with solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You share &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; via iCloud with all pupils in read-only mode. Each pupil shares an iCloud folder &lt;strong&gt;F[i]&lt;/strong&gt; with you read-only, in which they put their filled-in assignments and you share an iCloud folder &lt;strong&gt;C[i]&lt;/strong&gt; with each pupil, where you will put corrections and correct solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
